[
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Joomla is an open source Content Management System (CMS) written in PHP. It is a very popular CMS along with WordPress and Drupal. It facilitates users to develop online applications and websites. Joomla is built on model-view-controller (MVC) web application framework.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "A Mambot is a small, task-oriented function, mini program or plugin. It is used to modify content before display, extend site search, add core functionality etc. Mambots are renamed plugins in Joomla 1.5.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Mambots can be divided into 5 types/categories that are displayed by filtering in the filter field:\nADVERTISEMENT\nauthentication\ncontent\neditors\neditors-xtd\nsearch",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) What are the advantages of Joomla?",
        "answer": "Following are the main advantages of using Joomla:\nJoomla is open source and absolutely free to use.\nIt provides a lot of free components are available in extensions.joomla.org/\nIt has inbuilt permission and user role.\nOne click updation.\nProvide simple, elegant and user-friendly templates free to use.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Provide limited options\nPlugin compatibility may cause an issue.\nIts websites are heavy\nLimited server resources and efficiency",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "6) What is the homepage in Joomla?",
        "answer": "When you install Joomla, it has a menu link to the frontpage component which is by default the homepage of a site.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) What is position in Joomla?",
        "answer": "Joomla template displays pages in a specific format. It divides the pages into a number of modules like nav, header, footer, top, bottom, module, etc. This is known as position.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "8) What are the most useful and advanced features or add-ons in Joomla?",
        "answer": "Joomla framework has some very useful and advanced features that facilitate developers to build some specific applications and websites very easily and quickly. These are:\nInventory control systems\nData reporting tools\nApplication bridges\nCustom product catalogs\nIntegrated e-commerce systems\nComplex business directories\nReservation systems\nCommunication tools",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) Can Joomla be used as a blogging platform?",
        "answer": "Yes Joomla can also be used as a blogging platform. But other CMS should be preferred over Joomla for blogging purpose.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) Which database system does Joomla supports?",
        "answer": "Joomla supports MySQL database.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) By default how many tables Joomla have?",
        "answer": "By default, Joomla have 65 tables.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) How many Joomla tables are related with users?",
        "answer": "jos_users\njos_core_acl_aro\njos_core_acl_groups_aro_map",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) In which files database settings are stored in Joomla CMS?",
        "answer": "In Joomla CMS, database settings are stored in the root directory under configuration.php.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) What is the prefix that Joomla uses by default?",
        "answer": "Joomla have prefix like jos_.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Modules are the items which can be shown anywhere through the module manager in the administrative interface. They are used to extend the capability of Joomla by adding new functionalities to the software. Modules are installed in the admin section.\nA Joomla module may include:\nMain menu\nTop menu\nTemplate chooser\nNewsflash\nPolls\nHit counters etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) Which files are required to build module in Joomla?",
        "answer": "mod_module_name.php\nmod_module_name.xml",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) In which types of websites, Joomla is frequently used?",
        "answer": "It is used in following type of websites\nCorporate web portals\nOnline media websites\nNGO Websites\nPersonal pages\nSocial Media portals",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) What are the web services that Joomla supports?",
        "answer": "Remote Procedure Calls\nXML-RPC services",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) How to remove page title from the front page in a Joomla website?",
        "answer": "For this you have to a parameter setting in the front page component:\nLog in to the administrative backend.\nFrom the top menu select mainmenu under Menu option. Click Home.\nOn the right side, select Hide under the Page Title parameter.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "20) What are the components in Joomla?",
        "answer": "Components can be known as the main elements of Joomla's functionality. The core elements are:\nContents\nBanner\nPoll\nInformation\nnews feeds\nweb link",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Below files are necessary files to build a component in Joomla:\nOn admin side,\ncomponent_name.xml\ninstall.component_name.php\nuninstall.component_name.php\ntoolbar.component_name.php\nuninstall.component_name.html.php\nadmin.component_name.php\nadmin.component_name.html.php\ncomponent_name.class.php\nOn front side,\ncomponent_name.php\ncomponent_name.html.php",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "22) State whether content items can be assigned to multiple categories or sections?",
        "answer": "No. content items can't be assigned to multiple categories or sections.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) How to link inside content to another content item in Joomla?",
        "answer": "Get the URL for the page you want to link to. Then make a link using any editor or with HTML if you dont have WYSIWYG(Editor).",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "24) What is favicon? How can you change a favicon in Joomla?",
        "answer": "A favicon is an icon associated with a particular website, generally displayed in the address bar of the browser. You can change, manage and upload a new favicon by accessing global configuration site tab.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "25) How can you make a menu link that is not clickable?",
        "answer": "You can use a link type separator/placeholder to create a menu link that is not clickable (doesn't connect to anything).",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Joomla supports all types and size of websites.\nBusiness web sites\nOnline newspapers, magazines, etc\nNon-profit and organizational web sites\nCorporate web sites\nGovernment web sites\nFamily or personnel websites\nCommunity based portal",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "27) How Joomla is different in comparison to Drupal and WordPress?",
        "answer": "Joomla, Drupal and WordPress all are content management systems written in PHP. Let's check the difference among them.\nWordPress:\nIt is best for beginners.\nEasy to use.\nIt works well for small to medium sized websites & blogs.\nProvides a lot of themes, plugins and widgets.\n\nJoomla:\nIt is good for E-commerce type of sites, but requires at least some level of technical coding.\nIt is user-friendly but more complex site development option.\nDrupal:\nIt is the most difficult one, but also the most powerful CMS.\nIt requires some expertise and experience to operate.\nIt is used to develop most advanced websites.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "28) Why the SSL enabled option is set to on?",
        "answer": "The page link will be as \"https//..\" when you set the SSL enabled option is set to on.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "29) Which option would you choose for installed website metadata?",
        "answer": "We will choose the global information option.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "30) Which file is loaded for providing menu bar to admin interface?",
        "answer": "Loader.php file is loaded by index.php for providing menu bar.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "31) Can you control the desktop application with joomla?",
        "answer": "Despite of the fact that Joomla is intended for web applications but we can also control some desktop applications. Joomla server can communicate with desktop applications by following some standard protocols.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "32) Explain Breadcrumb Module in Joomla?",
        "answer": "Breadcrumb displays hierarchical representation with click able links for the users to determine where they are in the web site and allow them to navigate back.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "33) Explain Meta Description in Joomla Menu Manager?",
        "answer": "It is a short description of the page in an optional paragraph which is displayed in the results of search engines.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "TinyMCE Editor",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Extension manager extends the functionality of a Joomla website.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The Feed Display Module shows the RSS news feeds from a web site. It provides updated content to its user from other resources.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "This module displays the user's information that is accessing the web site.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Joomla templates:\nBeez3\nHathor\nIsis\nProtostar",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Content items can be defined as the HTML pages which are created and managed by the admin. Joomla has various categories of content items like X-category has 0 or more content pages. We can further classify categories in sections as one category has 0 more sections.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "joomla"
    }
]